# **Bitna Keum**

+82-10-3446-3606

beausty23.tistory.com

github.com/BitnaKeum



# **INTRODUCTION**

I am currently senior in Computer and Information Engineering at Kwangwoon University. I'm passionate about Natural Language Processing. My long-term goal is making human-like conversational chatbot which can even replace a 'real' friend. To realize my goal, I'm continuously studying various techniques of NLP and practicing modeling by myself. I want to deepen my understanding of the field of NLP, so I decide to go to graduate school. I'm looking forward to interacting with experienced professor and lab people to grow up.

## **EDUCATION**

## **Kwangwoon University**

Bachelor of Engineering, Department of Computer & Information Engineering GPA 4.16 / 4.5

Mar. 2017 - Feb. 2022 (Expected)
Seoul, South Korea

# **WORK EXPERIENCES**

Internship at TUNiB Inc.

Jul. 2021 - Present

Working as a data engineer at NLP company

Gangnam-gu, Seoul

- Contributing to building a hyperscale Korean language model
- Weekly NLP paper review
- Preparing to participate in NLP task competition (scheduled for Oct.)

• Internship at GNC Solution Co., Ltd.

Sep. 2019 - Feb. 2020

Studying Deep Learning and NLP

Songpa-gu, Seoul

- Developing Q&A Program based BERT
- Stock Analysis using LSTM and magic formula

Development Part-time Job at Esoftware Co., Ltd.

Oct. 2019 - Dec. 2019

Developing .NET framework Application Software

Songpa-gu, Seoul

- Software UI/UX Design
- Management of Database by SQL Query

# PROJECT EXPERIENCES

#### Hyperscale Korean-LM

Jul. 2021 - Present

- Progressing in internship
- Web scraping, data preprocessing, and data management

### Web Scraping Project

Jul. 2021 - Jul. 2021

- Personal project
- Scraping data from Namuwiki, Wikipedia, naver blog, daum blog, tistory, nate pann, youtube

## • Coin Price Prediction Project

May. 2021 - Jun. 2021

- Term project in Data Mining class
- To predict time-series data, tried various models (CNN, LSTM, Prophet, ARIMA, N-Beats)
- Got the best result using N-Beats with the profit of 2.23 times

## Thanks For Today: smart diary analyzing myself

Feb. 2021 - Feb. 2021

- Participated in SW-central-university Joint Hackathon as a school representative
- Analyzing the text data of diary by NLP
- Extracting the key word/sentence and frequent words, and Visualizing with Wordcloud

### GAN-based Clothing Design Application Program

Jul. 2020 - May. 2021

- Industry-Academic collaboration project with LG
- Applying StarGAN and Mask R-CNN and Providing service as Web application
- Improved the model architecture of StarGAN, resulted in better performance
- Made the model 35% lighter

## Consumer-Entrepreneur Connection Web Community

Jan. 2020 - Mar. 2020

- Developing Web for communication between consumer and (prospective) entrepreneur
- Back-end development with Javascript using Node.js
- NoSQL Database management
- Won an Excellence Award in Autonomous Semester Design & Development Project

## Developing BERT-based Q&A Program

Sep. 2019 - Feb. 2020

- Developing Q&A Program based BERT
- Trained the model on KorQuAD v1.0 dataset

## **EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITY**

#### • NLP Paper Reading Group 'Jibhyeonjeon'

Jun. 2021 - Present

- Intermediate class member
- Our team presented on the topic 'Task-Oriented Dialogue System'

#### Dacon Al Bit Trader Contest Season 2

May. 2021 - Jun. 2021

- Participated in the competition following the term project in Data Mining class
- Ranked 17th using N-Beats model with the profit of 2.23 times

## Idea Contest for Utilizing AI

Nov. 2020 - Nov. 2020

Won the 1st prize with the idea of 'Clothing pattern synthesis program using GAN'

### Coding School Tutor

Jan. 2019, Jan. 2021, Feb. 2021, Jul. 2021

- Working as a tutor of C and Python Coding School in Kwangwoon University
- Assisted and coached students in programming practice

• Tech Blog Mar. 2019 - Present

- Recording anything I learn while studying
- [Link]

## C-language Study

Mar. 2017 - Jun. 2017

- Studied C-language and algorithm every week
- Attended to several seminars

## Information Security Study

Mar. 2017 - Jun. 2017

- Studied overall Information Security, especially Reverse Engineering every week
- Founding member of Information Security Club

# **AWARDS AND HONORS**

2020 President's Award (1st place), Idea Contest for Utilizing AI, *Kwangwoon University*2020 Excellence Award, Autonomous Semester Design & Development Project, *Kwangwoon University*2021, 2020, 2018 Academic Excellence Scholarship, *Kwangwoon University* 

## **SKILLS**

#### Programming Skills

- Python (Skilled), C/C++ (Skilled), Java, JavaScript, SQL, R
- PyTorch, Tensorflow, Keras

#### Language Skills

Korean (Native), English (TOEIC 855), Chinese (Beginner)